ILGWU Company Files 5780/205
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU Company Files
1971-1995
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
5780/205
2.5 cubic feet
2.5 linear ft.
Records (documents).
Contains Dun and Bradstreet Report on companies, reports on the companies' activities with non-ILGWU firms, memoranda on companies and efforts to organize workers therein, as well as some authorization cards.
6766528
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
R. Miles, July 06, 2011
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 16, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.
Biographical / Historical
The ILGWU established the Department of Organization and Field Services in 1980. The department was responsible for, among other things, the coordination and survey of organizing activities, coordination and administration of information services including computer utilization, and the administration of all OSHA-related matters. It also coordinated the identification and implementation of new services.
As the ILGWU's central office for organizing, the Department of Organization and Field Services worked with affiliates of the international (e.g., local unions, district councils, and regional departments) in dealing with issues in their locations. In addition to working with union affiliates, the department also worked on legal and legislative fronts to ensure safe conditions for garment workers. Insofar as the department conducted surveys and gathered information, its work resembled that of the Research Department, and insofar as it supported pro-labor legislative efforts. To make clear the primary purpose of the Department of Organization and Field Services, the Report and Proceedings from the 1983 ILGWU Convention noted that, "The central concern is organization, and from this has stemmed the other broad activities which require skills, knowledge and information to be successful."
Scope and Contents
Taken together, the two collections comprising the records of the Department of Organization and Field Services provide a general sense of the work of the department, though they are not physically extensive. Organizing efforts by affiliate organizations of the ILGWU, and on which department staff assisted, may be documented in that affiliate's records or elsewhere in the ILGWU records.
Arranged alphabetically, these records (5780/144) include correspondence, memoranda, reports, printed material created or collected by the Organizing and Field Services Department, and other material relating to its activities dating from between 1961 and 1989. In addition to documenting routine operations of the department, these records also include documentation of efforts to roll back imports, including reports on congressional visits on a resolution on the subject. Also included are monthly reports on organizing activities from joint boards and regional departments, as well as periodic reports submitted by local unions', joint boards', and regional departments' organizing departments to the central organizing department; these reports include names of organizers and shops organized, and descriptions of current, future, and abandoned campaigns that were to be included in the Organizing Department's reports to the General Executive Board.
The ILGWU's company files (5780/205) contain Dun and Bradstreet Report on companies, reports on the companies' activities with non-ILGWU firms, memoranda on companies and efforts to organize workers therein, as well as some authorization cards.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780: ILGWU records 5780/144: ILGWU Organizing Department Records 5619/012: ACTWU Company Files
Air Filters, Inc.; Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union; Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union. Research Dept.; Beldoch Industries; Bill Coat; Billy Jack for Her; Camden Tannery; Country Miss; Dexter Shoe; Expo, Inc.s; Franklin Mushroom Farms, Inc. (Williamantic, Conn.); Gem Knits, Inc.; Gianni Sportswear; Glamour Blouse; Her Majesty Industries; JA Knitting Mills; King Sales; Mousefeathers, Inc.; Royal Silk; Ruby International; Sawyer of Napa; Sawyer of Napa/Press; Smoler Brothers Wicker Park; Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees; UNITE HERE (Organization); Winter Coat
6766528
- A & A Manufacturing, 1988-1991 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- A & S Sportswear, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- A Brod, Inc., 1990 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- AD & ME (Hialeah, FL), 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Action Apparel, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- ADA Outerwear, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Adena Sportswear, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Air Filters, Inc., 1982-1990 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Alema Knits, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Alixandre, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- All Kind Quilting, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Allison Tracy (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Alyce Designs, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- American Bazaar, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Animal Crackers, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Apex Box, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Apparel Affiliates, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Applied Accessories, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- At Last, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- AVI Sewing Corp., 1987 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- B F D Industries, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Baby Fair Inc., 1988-1990 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Bara Fashions, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Baronessa John, 1986-1989 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Barrow Industries Inc., 1990 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Beau-David (Expo, Inc.), 1983-1994 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Beldoch Industries, 1983-1991 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Billy Coat, 1981-1993 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Billy Jack for Her, 1981-1993 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Bloomingdale by Mail Ltd., Inc., 1990 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Body Spirit, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Bolero Clairtex, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Bomaine Corp., 1990 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Brenner International, 1988-1990 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Camden Tannery, 1983-1991 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Camelot Creations, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Cameo Courtures, Inc., 1988-1990 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Caron/Caprino, 1988-1990 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Carroll Reed, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Certified Lumber (IDA Loan), 1989 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Chang Lung Ind., 1991 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Charles Jourdan, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Charlotte Neville, 1987-1990 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- City Girl, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Colbert, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Collegetown, 1984-1987 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Costume Gallery, 1984-1989 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Country Miss, 1981-1990 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Cullinane Maureen, 1988-1990 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- DMAS Corp., 1989 (Box 1, Folder 50)
- DEB Shops, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Dexter Shoe/ Pam Am Shoe, 1983-1989 (Box 1, Folder 52)
- Di Fini, Inc., 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 53)
- Don Elliot, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 54)
- Eastern Apparel, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 55)
- Elan, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 56)
- EMSIG Mfg., 1988 (Box 1, Folder 57)
- Fairview Paper Box, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 58)
- Fashion Rite, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 59)
- Franklin Mushroom Farms, Inc., 1990 (Box 1, Folder 60)
- Fuller Brush, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 61)
- G & G Uniform Co., Inc., 1990 (Box 1, Folder 62)
- G T Sportswear, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 63)
- Gem Knits Inc. Gem Knitting Mills, 1988-1993 (Box 1, Folder 64)
- Gianni Sportswear, 1990-1995 (Box 1, Folder 65)
- Gibor Knitting, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 66)
- Ginger Peachy, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 67)
- Glamour Blouse, 1975-1989 (Box 1, Folder 68)
- Goodbuys/Lockewill, 1987-1989 (Box 1, Folder 69)
- Goodwill-Evansville, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 70)
- Graff California wear, Inc., 1990 (Box 1, Folder 71)
- Greater El Paso Corp., 1990 (Box 1, Folder 72)
- Grumbacher, S. and Son, Inc., 1989 (Box 1, Folder 73)
- H&M of California, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 74)
- HR Kaminsky and Sons, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 75)
- Her Majesty Industries, 1976-1987 (Box 1, Folder 76)
- Hickory Hills, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 77)
- High Fashion Garment/D.G.D., 1990 (Box 1, Folder 78)
- Hi Lo Mfg Co., 1990 (Box 1, Folder 79)
- Horchow Mail Order, Inc., 1991 (Box 1, Folder 80)
- Hotsy Totsy, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 81)
- House of Perfection, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 82)
- Howard B. Wolf, Inc., 1990 (Box 1, Folder 83)
- In Group Limited, 1986-1990 (Box 1, Folder 84)
- Its Jack, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 85)
- Ivy Brown, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 86)
- J & B Knitting Mills, 1988-1992 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- J & L Mfg., 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- JA Knitting Mills, 1984-1989 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- JRE, Inc., 1989 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Jasper Sportswear, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Jay Dee Sportswear, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Jeanette Maternities, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Jessica Howard, 1990-1992 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Jet Styles, 1987-1990 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Johnny Apple Seed, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Joyce, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Kids-At-Large, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Kids R Us, 1987-1989 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- King Sales, 1971-1990 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Klein and Co. (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Knit waves (Ellen Gang), 1990 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Kutty Fashions, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- L Luria and Sons, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- La Clase, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- La Mode, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Lease ways, 1987-1989 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Live-It-Up, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Loral Packaging, Inc., 1986 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- MAG/MDP, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Manny Industries, 1986-1988 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Members Only, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Miss Challenge Inc., 1990 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Moonlighting Studio, Inc. (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Mopac, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Mouse feathers, Inc., 1983-1993 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Muri-Lu Knitting Mills, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Nancy Johnson/ Press, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- National Embroidered Emblem Inc., 1988 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- New Yorker Dance Frocks, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Newark Auto Tops, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Omni Knit, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Orbit Instrument, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Paulette Fashions, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Periwinkle, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Pick Your Part Auto Wrecking, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Plastiflex, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Portier Rene, Inc., 1989 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Prophecy Corp., 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- R & M Kaufman, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- RBA Mfg, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 45)
- RJMJ, 1987-1989 (Box 2, Folder 46)
- Rangell Blas Co., 1986 (Box 2, Folder 47)
- Realite Optical, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 48)
- Roam Corp Roberta, Inc., Hollywood Nites, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 49)
- Rousso Apparel Group, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 50)
- Royal Silk, 1984-1990 (Box 2, Folder 51)
- Rubies Costumes, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 52)
- Ruby International, 1983-1988 (Box 2, Folder 53)
- St. Anna, Inc., 1989 (Box 2, Folder 54)
- Sawyer of Napa, 1990-1994 (Box 2, Folder 55)
- Sawyer of Napa/General Company Information, 1989-1991 (Box 2, Folder 56)
- Sawyer of Napa/Campaign Documents, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 57)
- Sawyer of Napa/Press, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 58)
- Sawyer of Napa/Customers, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 59)
- Sawyer of Napa/Suppliers, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 60)
- Scandia Trading Co., 1987-1990 (Box 2, Folder 61)
- SEMA Dist, Inc., 1989 (Box 2, Folder 62)
- Shaker Sportswear, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 63)
- Sharlee MFG/Inner World, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 64)
- Shufra Chocolate Food, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 65)
- Simpatica LTD/St. Gillian, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 66)
- Smart Novelty Blouse and Contractors (Darwood), 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 67)
- Smoler Brothers Wicker Park, 1985-1990 (Box 2, Folder 68)
- Snow White/American, 1987-1986 (Box 2, Folder 69)
- Somerset Knit, Philadelphia, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 70)
- Sport Pillows, 1987-1989 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Steven Michaels, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Suitables, ETX., 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Sun Distributions, Inc., 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Sunrise Fashions, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Swede Los Angles, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Sweet Sage (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Synari Ltd., 1989-1991 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Tanner Companies, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Technical Coated Fabric, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- T H M Strike [Folder 1 of 2], 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- T H M Strike [Folder 2 of 2], 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Tif and Griff Designs, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- TLC for Girls, Inc., 1990 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Tococco, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Trend Knits, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Tri Chen, Inc. (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Tribecca Corp, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Trimtex Knitting Mills, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Tripple O Enterprise, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Trutrim Corp., 1988 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Ultra Knit, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Ursela of Switzerland, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Victoria Royal, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Virginia Metals, 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Vogue Alley, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Walsh Super Service, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Weinmac Mfg., 1988 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- West End Affiliate, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Winter Coat, 1983-1990 (Box 3, Folder 30)